Mohamed Moustafa

Software Engineer

(updated at resume.fairewinds.ca)

https://fairewinds.ca

hi@fairewinds.ca

in LinkedIn: omtimoustafa

GitHub: <a>@mtimoustafa

SUMMARY

I'm a full-stack software engineer with 8 years of experience in SaaS-based platforms. I specialize in design systems and web accessibility. I also have experience leading projects and cross-team initiatives. In my free time I play music, read, and work on coding projects.

SKILLS

UI frameworks Design systems WCAG 2.0/2.1 acessibility

Microservice API design and Containerised architecture development deployment

TECH STACK

Javascript / Vue.js Ruby / R

Ruby / Ruby on Rails HTML / CSS / SCSS

Docker / Kubernetes MySQL / PostgreSQL AWS

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full work experience available on LinkedIn

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

GITLAB

December 2022 - Present Remote

- Led a 7-member project to enable purchasing & provisioning of Duo Enterprise, a key AI offering, driving 5-figure user sign-ups. Tech stack: Vue, Javascript, Ruby on Rails, GraphQL, PostgreSQL.
- Frontend maintainer of the GitLab Customers Portal; responsible for merging and deploying merge (pull) requests, improving local instance deployment, and updating documentation.
- Member of the GitLab accessibility working group, championing Customers

 Portal accessibility and bringing it up to par with the core GitLab application
- Co-ordinated and implemented an internal SKU rename, in collaboration with the Finance department, ensuring data integrity is maintained between GitLab and a critical third-party service.
- Created a universal Makefile command for running the Customers Portal locally, consolidating different ways of running various services into one simple, unified approach.
- Created a Rake task to periodically populate a database table with product-critical user information. Each data cohort contained 150,000+ records.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

VIDYARD

April 2017 - July 2021 Kitchener, Ontario, Canada

- Helped implement and maintain internal design system using Vue.js. The design system is used across all front-end services in the platform.
- Guild lead of internal design system. The guild (working group) consisted of 6+ engineers, designers, and QAs, and governed future goals and maintainership.
- Maintainer of key platform services, primarily using Ruby on Rails and Vue.js.
 Responsible for code reviews, refactoring and bugfixing, deploys, and mentorship.
- Responsible for upgrading major and most-trafficked parts of the platform to WCAG AA 2.0 accessibility standards.
- Mentored co-workers on how to develop for accessibility in a technical and design capacity.
- Led a project to create a new search feature. Refactored RESTful API endpoints and improved the existing ElasticSearch implementation.
- Refactored a stand-alone microservice to use Docker, Kubernetes, Skaffold, and OAuth, in order to integrate it into our development environment.
- Improved Vidyard Chrome Extension features and UI, using React.js.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

2011 - 2016

Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

BASc. with Honours, Computer Engineering, Co-operative (Internship) Program

CONFERENCES

- VueConf Toronto (2019, 2020)
- #a11yTO Accessibility Toronto (2019)
- University of Guelph Accessibility Conference (2018, 2019)

INTERESTS

LANGUAGES	English	Arabic	German	Dutch
	(native)	(native)	(learning)	(learning)

INTERESTS

- Former member of diversity+inclusion & wellness committees.
- Former volunteer at community initiatives in Ontario, Canada.
- I build and maintain small coding projects, including a financial transactions sync tool, running Minecraft in Docker, and this resume's generator.
- I play the guitar, bass and piano & experiment with music production.